theloop.com.au 2017-06-03

# Online Creative Portfolios and Creative Jobs - The Loop

This is The Loop’s Privacy Policy.  It explains how we collect, use and handle any personal information we collect from you when you use The Loop website. We understand your disclosure of personal information is a serious matter.  So, the protection and appropriate use of your personal information is important to us.

In this Privacy Policy the term “personal information” has the same meaning as in the Australian _Privacy Act_ 1988 and includes information that can be used to personally identify you.

**Collecting your personal information**

When you use The Loop we will collect various information about you or relating to you:

  * if you register to become a user of The Loop; 
  * if you send us a message from The Loop or otherwise;
  * as you visit web pages on The Loop; and
  * from your activities in connection with your use of The Loop.

**Becoming a user of The Loop**

Before you can access and use all of The Loop’s features and services, you must register to become a user of The Loop (by agreeing to The Loop’s [Terms & Conditions](https://www.theloop.com.au/terms "The Loop Terms & Conditions")).

To register, we ask that you provide us with certain personal information, which will generally include your name, address, phone number, email address, date of birth, academic record, profile picture and personal website (each to allow The Loop to customise your experience), a username and a password created by you. You may also elect to upload materials to your profile that include personal information.

**How we use your personal information**

We use your personal information to create and maintain your user account and profile for The Loop and to provide you with the services we offer through The Loop.

Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, we may use personal information to: 

  * send you information about your account, the services we or our related companies provide or any changes or upgrades that we make to those services;
  * to alert you of relevant opportunities and activities (including, without limitation, jobs, workspaces, content and notifications (for example, if another user is following your profile));
  * to send you newsletters which you may either elect to receive or may be interested in given your user account and/or profile; and/or
  * to provide you with any other information or services you request that we provide.

Except as set out in this Privacy Policy or otherwise agreed by you, we will not share your personal information with third parties (such as marketing companies) or use your personal information other than for The Loop’s internal purposes. 

**Sending messages from The Loop**

We may provide ‘support’ links on The Loop that enable you to send emails directly to us (for example, if you need assistance with any of our services or generally in relation to The Loop). We will retain emails you send for the purposes of contacting you and for our internal purposes.

**Cookies**

The Loop uses ‘cookies’ to identify information about your web browser session and personalisation data each time you visit The Loop. A ‘cookie’ is a small data file that will be stored by your web browser when you access The Loop.  These cookies do not contain any of your personal information such as name or email, the information stored in the cookie will only identify you to The Loop.

Cookies can be used to enhance your use of The Loop, as we use them to help personalise The Loop’s delivery of services and material to you, such as information which is most relevant to your profile and interests.

You can set up your browser so that it does not accept our cookies. You can also manually delete our cookies from your browser.  However, you will not be able to login to The Loop with out cookies being enabled on your browser. When browsing without logging in, some features may not behave as intended when cookies are not accepted.

**How we may share your information**

We may engage third parties to undertake some of The Loop’s services or related services such as hosting, archiving, data security and email communications.  We may provide those third parties access to personal information for the sole purpose of them providing their services to us. We will use reasonable endeavours to ensure that those third parties only use your personal information for the specific purposes for which it is provided to them and consistently with this Privacy Policy.

We may also disclose your personal information:

  * to our related companies;
  * to our professional advisors;
  * to law enforcement authorities, if we suspect that an unlawful act is being committed or that such disclosure will prevent that unlawful act; or
  * as otherwise required or authorised by law.

If you apply for a position that is advertised via The Loop, we will provide your contact details to the person or company advertising that position.  

Similarly, if you have been sent a “handshake” from another user of The Loop to get in contact with them, we will facilitate them to contact you via The Loop and display certain details about your availability (if you have filled that information), however, your personal information is not shared with them.

Other than the types of disclosures set out in this Privacy Policy or as otherwise agreed by you, we will not disclose your personal information to any third party.

**Security of your personal information**

We will use reasonable security measures to protect your personal information from loss or unauthorised access, use or disclosure.

**Your access to your personal information**

You are entitled to know what personal information we hold about you. You are also entitled to update or correct your personal information. If you would like to contact us in relation to your personal information, please do so by email to privacy@theloop.com.au.

**Third party websites**

Please be aware that The Loop may contain links to third party websites. If you visit such websites, before providing your personal information on or in connection with those websites, we suggest you review the privacy policy and terms and conditions of use of the third party website.
